number 27 and that's the final part of
the teaching on refuge in the Lum room
okay what happens next in Guadalajara we
go to Karma we start studying karma and
the DCI people are going to be excited
in Guadalajara because then we go deep
into the laws of karma you know the four
laws of karma and the four flowers and
all that's going to come in Guadalajara
okay so we'll be finished with refuge
this week and then in Guadalajara in
August July we will do comma just coma
coma coma okay so if you really ever
wanted to know about Karma
come to that okay it's a very detailed
teaching about Karma
okay how does common work so the last
last last refuge meditation the last
last last advice in the lamb rim by the
way this is called milk tea no tea is as
opposed to picking means teach
the people the scripture known team
means put them in between and let them
experience that Lamia level you know
teach them meditations that will help
them to experience refuge so we're doing
both we're doing pity I'm explaining the
book to you then you're going to go do
it young to you and yum tea you're going
to go put the teaching into personal
experience okay and that's another way
to do love them if you do a tough
laundry program you teach people you
know the eight la mia books together
it's called
sorry well he used 8 4 is also
traditional for great books on mom room
and that takes a long long time and then
you require that the student reached
that level before they can go on to the
next one you test them are they taking
refuge six times a day you test them and
if they're not you don't let them go to
karma but it would be impractical is
because I'd have to do karma over like a
hundred times okay
it's for a Lama who has a few good
students okay like that alright so
number twenty-seven the final refuge
teaching which we will get to in the
book out I hope after the three-day
retreat its he says something very cool
he says look either jump or don't jump
okay don't stand on the cliff you know
did you have a jump off when I was close
into their ocean I think I did it once
it's really scary you know and you say
oh I could do that you know and your
friend says okay let me see you do it
and you go up to the edge and you look
over and he said I don't know maybe I
can't do it doesn't hurt too much if you
if you land on your feet he's going to
land on his head that hurts but it
doesn't hurt too much and if you don't
hit a rock so he says don't stand on the
top and go I don't know you know this is
I don't know if I want to do this or not
don't in English we say don't be
wishy-washy don't say I don't know if I
want to do it or not you know maybe I'll
do it maybe I want you know he says if
you're going to take refuge jump just
jump okay
stop using science start do you think
please okay just jump okay and he says
don't around
okay like just jump
the last refuge advice is go for it man
what the hell just don't you know start
using seeds to run your life you know
stop thinking about doctors and jobs and
you know marriage counselors just jump
start using seeds for everything okay so
maybe you can do that meditation on
Thursday morning okay in my jumping or
not just jump you know by Thursday
morning you're supposed to be like the
meditation is that the calm of Diamond
Mountain Retreat Kevin finally reached
your mind and in that enlightened space
you decide I'm changing from now on I'm
going to jump no more no more like I
don't know I don't know okay from now on
seed seed sweets okay for everything I
want okay I don't okay by Thursday
morning I do this last okay Thursday
morning meditations okay what time is it
[Music]
yeah at 7:15 at 7:45 on Thursday in the
morning do this meditation at 7:45 on
Thursday morning which is your last
serious meditation during the three days
did this one I'm going to jump or I'm
not going to jump so don't do it before
that okay save it for the end because
hopefully by that time the retreat
cottage had an effect on your mind and
you will have more courage you know I'm
going to jump no more self-existent a
space you know I'm jumping
I'm going for it okay that should do
your last meditation okay all right then